Hemant Bangera

Mobile: +91 8108160981

Email: hemantbangera16@gmail.com

Sales, Marketing And Operations Executive

Entrepreneurial executive with more than 15 years of experience managing sales, marketing and operations for both start up and established organizations. elevator

Looking for a challenging and responsible position where experience and personal abilities will have valuable application.

Professional Experience:

BoxMySpace – Senior Sales Manager – December 2019 - September 2022

BoxMySpace is a 3PL service provider based out of Mumbai. We offer storage, fulfilment and last mile delivery services to the clients.

Job Profile: Senior Sales Manager

- Work in partnership with senior leaders of the company to execute current objectives and develop a plan for future organizational needs.
- Attend (via phone) all weekly department (account managers, carrier sales, sales) meetings to discuss
 pricing, service issues, KPI metrics, communications, training and any related items.
- Utilize business development skills to identify, qualify and develop relationships with prospective customers and independently generate new sales revenue.
- Track and maintain all sales activity in the company CRM.
- Develop potential strategic carrier following for dedicated business.
- Develop and maintain strong carrier relationships.
- Source and secure freight coverage by any method including but not limited to; internet searches, past contacts, current carriers, website leads, business development leads, sales agent leads and other client leads.

Collaborate with team on details required to ensure most effective solutions to customers and our carrier

partners.

- Develop and manage KPI measurements, goals and processes for departmental accountability.
- Complete pricing and bid packages and provide feedback to team on rates submitted.
- Negotiate rates to meet margin objectives and drive revenue.
- Effectively utilize data and problem-solving skills to proactively resolve customer and carrier issues.
- Communicate all potential problems with senior company leaders.
- Travel as business requires.
- Other duties as assigned.

Ceasefire Industries Pvt .Ltd (May 2017 till December 2019)

Ceasefire I.P.Ltd is a leading manufacturer in the fire safety equipment segment. Headquartered in Noida and having more than 300 offices all over India, it is one of the leading player in the fire safety industry with having 360 degree solutions related to fire safety.

Job Profile: HOL - Direct Vertical - Sales

- . Leading 5 member team.
- . Making cold call and accompanied calls with new and old team members.
- . Ensuring improvement in team productivity.
- . Making sure of achieving targets.
- . Making sure that daily planning execution is according to the actual planning of the day.
- . Keeping all sales record up to date of the team members in the CRM.
- . Seeing to it that all company policies are followed by the team members.
- . Keeping a track of monthly planning.
- . Market research and gathering new data.
- . Leave approval.

Kedar Elevators (October 2009 - April 2017)

Kedar elevators were involved in maintaining and modernisation of passenger, goods and all other forms of elevators in Mumbai, Thane and Navi Mumbai with HO in Thane and branch office in the eastern suburbs. Job Profile: Asst. Sales Manager

Responsibilities:

- Making cold calls for new clients.
- Taking appointments for personal meeting to present the company profile and services.
- Retention of old clients by regular visits.
- Preparing quotation, discussion and finalizing the contract.
- Built a team capable of supporting the operational and sales requirements.
- Checking on daily basis breakdown calls.
- Records of repeated complaints attended by service technician to be maintained properly & inform the management for necessary action.
- Reporting to HOD about repeated calls and informing complaint not attended timely.
- Monitor renewal of AMC done with 10-15% hike as compared to last year rate.
- Supervise whether revised letters have been sent to the client.
- Ensure AMC rates are finalized with customers in consultation with HOD.
- Ensure the daily reporting of team to HOD about AMC follow up done with the client.
- Monitor the regular update of data.
- Check the letters for renewal of AMC to clients.
- Check the AMC agreements.
- Managed activities on a day to day basis and took overall responsibility for the effective and efficient running
 of the operation. Planned the resource requirements (people, equipment, inventory).

AirCheck India Pvt. Ltd. - 30th August 2004 - 11th June 2009

AirCheck is the pioneer and leading organization in media monitoring in the country covering all the mediums of media catering to US, UK, Australia, NZ and India.

Process Trainer

Job Profile

- Responsibilities included coaching new employees with various protocols and procedures of the company.
- Conduct training sessions on the various aspects of the process.
- Providing feedback after budding to enhance quality of agents as per process requirement.
- Addressing complaints and resolving problems within the training group.
- Reporting any issue with regards to technical/quality/operations on daily basis.
- Responsible for the attendance and discipline of the team.
- Creating reports on basis of the collated data on daily basis.

Team Leader

- Responsible for the attendance and discipline of the team.
- Assigning work to the employees.
- Delegating and monitoring work of the team members on daily basis.
- · Identifying and training team members.
- Meeting deadlines laid down for the assigned task and projects.
- Reporting any issue with regards to technical/quality/operations to the concerned technical/project managers. Quality Analyst
- To monitor media enquiries and ensure that all databases are updated on a daily basis.
- Write reports; collate data through web search related to the assigned market segments.
- Data analyzing.
- Training new executives in new software.

 Quality Check.

GRT Ship Management Pvt. Ltd. - 14th June 2001 - 25th July 2004

- Cargo booking for LCL for US, Gulf, Europe & Far East.
- On field client calling.
- Documentation

Sales Executive – Delhi

Job Profile - Same as above

Sales in Charge - Pune

- Developing customer base in Pune.
- Handling team of 2 sales executive, documentation & customer service.
- Reporting to Mumbai head office.

Education:

B.Com – Commercial University (Privately)-Delhi -2009

H.S.C – St. Xavier's Junior College – 1998 S.S.C

- St. Francis Xavier's High School - 1996

Certification:

NIIT – (1 Year Basic Programming)

Personal Details

Contact Address: D-3 Shilpkar CHS, RTO Lane, 4 Bungalows, Andheri (W)

D.O.B: 16th June, 1980

Languages Known: English, Hindi, Marathi & Tulu

Hobbies: Travelling & Reading

Reference: As and when required.

I do hereby declare that all information furnished above is true to best of my knowledge belief.

Date:

Hemant Bangera